A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Cox and Reece Investigations FA418
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, Cox and Reece Investigations, 1952-1954
1917-1969 (Bulk: 1952-1954)
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA418
36.97 Cubic Feet 93 containers
Related Archival Material note
Rockefeller Foundation records, RG 3.2 Administration, Program and Policy (including but limited to: Series 900 General Program and Policy, Box 18, Folder 103) Rockefeller Foundation records, RG 1 Projects; Rockefeller Foundation records, RG 12 Officer's Diaries; General Education Board Collection; Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial records; Foundation Center Collection; Wormser, Rene A. Foundations: Their Power and Influence. Devin-Adair, New York: 1958.
Biographical/Historical note
History of the Cox and Reece Investigations at the Rockefeller Foundation
The Cox and Reece Investigation files document the Rockefeller Foundation and General Education Board's preparation for and response to investigations by the United States House of Representatives Select Committee to Investigate Tax-Exempt Foundations and Comparable Organizations, which were held between 1952-1954. The first investigation was headed by Edward Eugene Cox (R-Georgia) and the second by B. Carroll Reece (R-Tennessee).
The Cox investigation involved subpoenaed responses to a lengthy questionnaire, followed by hearings, at which Dean Rusk, president of the Rockefeller Foundation, testified for the Foundation and the General Education Board, which was inactive, but which maintained a corporate existence whose affairs were administered by the Foundation.
The Reece investigation also involved responses to written questions, but hearings were not held. In the course of the investigations, the political orientation of various organizations was scrutinized, including the Rockefeller Foundation and the GEB, in part by focusing on the political orientation of grant and fellowship recipients, both individuals and institutions.
Biographical/Historical note
Edward Eugene Cox
Representative from Georgia; born near Camilla, Mitchell County, Ga., April 3, 1880; attended the grade schools, Camilla High School, the academic department of Mercer University, Macon, Ga., for nearly four years, and was graduated from the law department of that university in 1902; was admitted to the bar the same year and commenced practice at Camilla, Ga.; mayor of Camilla 1904-1906; delegate to the Democratic National Convention in 1908; appointed and subsequently elected judge of the superior court of the Albany circuit and served from 1912 until he resigned in 1916, having become a candidate for Congress; unsuccessful candidate for election in 1916 to the Sixty-fifth Congress; elected as a Democrat to the Sixty-ninth and to the thirteen succeeding Congresses and served from March 4, 1925, until his death; chairman, Select Committee on Tax Exempt Foundations (Eighty-second Congress); had been reelected to the Eighty-third Congress; died in Bethesda, Md., December 24, 1952; interment in Oakview Cemetery, Camilla, Ga.1.
http://clerk.house.gov/art_history/mem_bio/index.html
Biographical/Historical note
B. Carroll Reece
(husband of Louise G. Reece), a Representative from Tennessee; born on a farm near Butler, Johnson County, Tenn., December 22, 1889; attended the public schools, Watauga Academy, Carson-Newman College, New York University, and the University of London; assistant secretary and instructor in the New York University in 1916 and 1917; during the First World War enlisted in May 1917 and served with the American Expeditionary Forces from October 1917 to July 1919; was decorated with the Distinguished Service Cross, Distinguished Service Medal, Purple Heart, and the French Croix de Guerre with Palm; director of the School of Business Administration of New York University in 1919 and 1920; elected as a Republican to the Sixty-seventh and to the four succeeding Congresses (March 4, 1921-March 3, 1931); unsuccessful candidate for reelection in 1930 to the Seventy-second Congress; elected to the Seventy-third and to the six succeeding Congresses (March 4, 1933-January 3, 1947); was not a candidate for renomination in 1946; delegate to the Republican National Conventions in 1928, 1932, 1936, 1940, 1944, and 1948; lawyer, banker, and publisher; member of the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution in 1945 and 1946; chairman of the Republican National Committee 1946-1948; unsuccessful candidate for election to the United States Senate in 1948; elected to the Eighty-second and to the five succeeding Congresses and served from January 3, 1951, until his death in Bethesda, Md., March 19, 1961; chairman, Special Committee on Tax Exempt Foundations (Eighty-third Congress); interment in Monte Vista Burial Park, Johnson City, Tenn.2.
http://clerk.house.gov/art_history/mem_bio/index.html
Scope and Contents note
The preponderance of the collection consists of various summaries of the Rockefeller Foundation and GEB grant administration files prepared by the Foundation staff for use by senior staff and Foundation counsel as they responded to written questions from the Cox and Reece investigations and as they prepared for Dean Rusk's testimony at the Cox committee hearing.
The collection is indexed with a number and letter system that made efficient research feasible, in case such reference work had been needed during live testimony. Card indexes also exist.
Although most of the information that appears in these records also occurs in grant administration and program and policy files of the Rockefeller Foundation and the General Education Board, as the case may be, the format of these records and the configurations of the information make the records unique in the context of the Foundation and the GEB collections, and offer insight into how the Foundation responded to the congressional investigations.
Two particular aspects of the Cox and Reece Investigation files not duplicated in the main body of the Rockefeller Foundation and the General Education Board records are the source and citation summaries, as well as the subject files and those documenting the political climate.
Arrangement note
The records are arranged into four series: Series 1 Digest Files; Series 2 Witness Statements; Series 3 Washington D.C. Files; and Series 4 Background Information and Miscellaneous.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
- Digest Files, 1; 13.54 Cubic Feet 22 letter document boxes and 11 legal document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Digest Files contain materials from the Rockefeller Foundation, China Medical Board, General Education Board and Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial grant and fellowship administration files relating to specific grants to individuals, institutions and projects, to general subjects such as program, policy and propaganda to the personnel. Separate files for individuals and specific projects are arranged numerically and are recorded both in a numerical and alphabetical sheet index. Most of this material was prepared for the Cox investigation and the details of its preparation are described in Mr. Albrights' memorandum re: The Scope and Method of Preparation for the Cox Committee Investigation. During the Reece investigation new material was added to these files and these new files were prepared the same way. The files added during the Reece investigation are typed on blue paper. In addition to the information in the sheet indices names referred to in the digests prepared for the Cox investigation and names of the persons supported by the grants for Regional Studies.
  - A - Council on Foreign Relations, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B - New School For Social Research- General, 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1 - Cornell University: Russian Studies, Simmons, Ernest J., 1939-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Chinese Languages Studies, 1935-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 3 - American Council of Learned Societies: Slavic Studies, 1943-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 4 - American Council of Learned Societies: Mongolian Studies, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 5 - American Council of Learned Societies: Russian Publications, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 6 - Library of Congress: Far Eastern Studies, 1933-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 7 - Library of Congress: Russian Collections: Distributions, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 8 - Library of Congress: Russian Collections: Microfilming, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 9 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Russian Language School, 1934-1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 10 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Japanese Communism Study, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 11 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Far Eastern Issues (Inquiry Series), 1938-1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 12 - Russia: 1947 Exchange of USSR and US Social Scientists, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 13 - Russia - Public Health Visit to US, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 14 - Russia: Princeton Mathematics Conference, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 15 - Russia: Exchange of Scientists: 1944, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 16 - American - Soviet Science Society, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 17 - American Soviet Medical Society, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 18 - Eurasia Research Institute, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 19 - Committee for Rehabilitation of Polish Science and Culture Book Purchases, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 20 - Columbia University: Russian Studies, 1943-1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 21 - Amerika Institut, University of Munich, Peters, H. F., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 22 - New School for Social Research: Totalitarian Communications Studies, 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 23 - New School for Social Research, Lehmann - Haupt, Hellmut, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 24 - Spanish Exiles: 1940, University of Mexico: School of Medicine, 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 25 - Association of Documentary Film Procedures, 1939-1952 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 26 - American Film Center: Rosten, 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 27 - American Film Center: Benoit - Levy, 1942-1952 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 28 - American Film Center: English Teaching Films, 1942-1952 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 29 - American Film Center: Gorer, 1939-1952 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 30 - American Film Center: Slesinger, 1938-1952 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 31 - American Film Center: National Committee on International Intellectual Cooperation, 1939-1952 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 32 - Library of Congress: Wartime Communications Study, 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 33 - Free Trade Committee: Visits of Union Leaders, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 34 - Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 35 - University of Montreal: Slavic Studies, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 36 - School of Social Sciences, Helsinki, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 37 - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 38 - American Council on Education: Cultural Exchange Commission, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 39 - American Council on Education: Far Eastern Teaching, 1942-1952 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 40 - University of California: Far Eastern Studies, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 41 - Institute of Pacific Relations Counsel's File, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 41A - Institute of Pacific Relations: 1925-1926, 1925-1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 41B - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 41C - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 41D - Institute of Pacific Relations: General, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - 41E - Institute of Pacific Relations: 1932-1940, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - 41F - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - 41G - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - 41H - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - 41I - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - 41J - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - 41K - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - 41L - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - 41M - Institute of Pacific Relations: 1949, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - 41N - Institute of Pacific Relations: 1950, 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - 41O - Institute of Pacific Relations: 1951, 1947-1952 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - 41P - Institute of Pacific Relations: 1952 to Date, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - 42 - Cornell University: Civil Liberties Study: Walter Gellhorn, 1942-1954 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - 42 - Civil Liberties: Book Reviews, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 43 - Statistical Institute of Economic Research, Bulgaria: Dodoff, B., 1932-1952 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - 44 - University of Pennsylvania: Indic Studies, 1947-1952 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - 45 - American Civil Liberties Union, 1941-1952 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - 46 - Refugee Scholars (Postwar): Iron Curtain Countries, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - 47 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Kohlberg Attack, 1944-1954 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - 48 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Fellowships: Council on Foreign Relations - Fellowships - Foreign Policy Association - Fellowships, 1932-1952 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - 49 - Salzburg Seminar, 1947-1952 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - 50 - Studies of Congress: 1946, Laski, Harold, 1940-1952 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - 51 - Communission of Inqury: Foreign Policy, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - 52 - Congress of Industrial Organizations - Visit of Union Leaders, 1948-1952 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - 53 - Carlsberg Foundation, Copenhagen, 1935-1952 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - 54 - Council on Foreign Relations: Langer Study of World War II, 1945-1954 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - 55 - Book Publishers Bureau - Trade Studies in China and Russia, 1943-1952 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - 56 - University of Zagreb (Yugoslavia): 1952, 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - 57 - Russia: Visiting Scholars to Russia - 1936-1937, Pares, Sir Bernard, 1936-1954 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - 58 - Russia: Training Russian Experts: 1946, 1946-1952 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - 59 - Foreign Policy Association: Publicizing Issues, Wallace, Henry A., 1934-1952 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - 60 - National Center of Scientific Research: Genetics, 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - 61 - National Center of Scientific Research: Equipment, 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - 62 - National Center of Scientific Research: Conferences, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - 63 - National Center of Scientific Research: General, 1947-1952 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - 64 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Rockefeller Foundation Minutes: Set 1, Institute of Pacific Relations - Rockefeller Foundation Grants in Aid, 1926-1952 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - 65 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Letters, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - 66 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Lists and Exhibits, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - 67 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Memos on Hearings, etc., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - 68 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Press Clippings, Articles, etc., 1951 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - 69 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Statements, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - 70 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Work Sheets, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - 71 - Far Eastern Association, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - 72 - University of Sao Paulo: Nuclear Physics, Wataghin, Gleb, 1940-1952 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - 73 - University of Chicago: Frankfurt Exchange Project, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - 74 - National Council of American - Soviet Friendship, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - 74A - Attorney General?s List: National Council of American - Soviet Friendship, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - 74B - Attorney General?s List: National Council of American - Soviet Friendship, 1945-1952 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - 74C - China Aid Council, Inc., 1946-1952 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - 74D - Association of Internes and Medical Students, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - 74E - Actors Laboratory, Incorporated (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - 74F - Group Theatre (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - 74G - World Youth Conference, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - 74H - Natioanl Institute of Arts & Letters, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - 74I - People's University, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - 74J - Attorney General's List: American Continental Peace Conference, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - 74K - Attorney General's List: Frontier Films, 1938-1952 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - 74L - Attorney General's List: Dramatic Workshop and Technical Institute, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - 74M - Attorney General's List: Hollywood Writers Mobilization, 1946-1952 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - 74N - Attorney General's List: Film Audiences for Democracy, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - 74O - Attorney General's List: Southern Conference for Human Welfare, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - 74P - Attorney General's List: Methodist Federation for Social Action, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - 74Q - Attorney General's List: California Labor School, Incorporated, 1944-1947 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - 74R - Attorney General's List: American Committee to Save Refugees, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - 74S - Attorney General's List: Emergency Peace Campaign, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - 74T - Attorney General's List: Open Road, Incorporated, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - 74U - Attorney General's List: Progressive Citizens of America, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - 74V - Attorney General's List: Joint Anti - Fascist Refugee Committee, 1939-1945 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - 74W - Attorney General's List: American Association of Scientific Workers, 1939-1945 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - 74X - Attorney General's List: Independent Citizens Committee of Arts, Sciences and Professions, Incorporated, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - 75 - New School for Social Research: Refugee Scholars: 1933-1940: General 1937-1948 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - 75A - New School for Social Research: Refugee Scholars: 1933-1940: Actions, 1931-1952 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - 75B - New School for Social Research: Refugee Scholars: 1940-1945: General, 1940-1947 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - 75C - New School for Social Research: Refugee Scholars: 1940-1945: Actions, 1933-1952 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - 76 - New School for Social Research: War and Peace Studies, 1939-1944 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - 77 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Communist China Study, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - 78 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Soviet Far Eastern Policy, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - 79 - Institute of Pacific Relations: Far Eastern Teaching: 1943, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - 80 - International Press Institute: 1951, 1950-1954 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - 81 - Yale University: Institute of International Studies, 1935-1952 (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - 82 - Yale University: Post War Studies: 1942, 1942-1952 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - 83 - Yale University: Far Eastern Studies Proposal, 1941-1952 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - 84 - Council on Foreign Relations: War and Peace Studies, 1939-1952 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - 85 - University of Alabama: Electoral Process in the South, 1945-1952 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - 86 - University of Chicago: Race Relations Study, 1947-1952 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - 87-1 - London School of Economics and Political Science, 1931-1954 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - 88 - Pasteur Institute, France, 1937-1952 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - 89 - Russia: Rockefeller Foundation Health Commission: 1941-1943, 1941-1952 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - 90 - American Russian Medical Council (Proposed), 1943 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - 91 - Commission on Interracial Cooperation, 1926-1943 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - 92 - Refugee Scholars: Pre-1945, Nikolajevsky, Boris, 1941-1952 (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - 92A - Refugee Scholars: Pre-1945, Bergstrasser, Arnold, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - 92B - Refugee Scholars: Pre-1945, Kulischer, Eugene, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - 92C - Refugee Scholars: Pre-1945, Polanyi, Karl, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - 92D - Refugee Scholars: Pre-1945, Dennery, Etienne, 1937-1940 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - 93 - Harvard University: International Relations Study, 1937-1952 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - 94 - University of California: Enemy Alien Study, 1942-1952 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - 95 - Tokyo University: Language and Thought Study: 1950, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - 96 - World Youth Congress, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - 97 - Deutsche Hochschule Fur Politik, 1931-1952 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - 98 - Current Digest of Soviet Press: American Council of Learned Societies: Social Science Research Council, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - 99 - Social Science Research Council, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - 99A - American Historical Association: Government Records Committee, 1935-1954 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - 99B - Harvard University: Slavic Studies, 1943-1952 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - 99C - Columbia University: Korean and Japanese Broadcasters, 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - 99D - Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America, 1948-1954 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - 99E - University of Copenhagen: Genetic Conferences, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - 99F - Society for Experimental Biology: England, 1946-1952 (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - 99G - World Peace Foundation: Dennett, Raymond, Alger Hiss, 1933-1952 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - 99H - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, United Nations Documentation - Alger Hiss, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - 99I - International Youth Library, Munich, 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - 99J - Price, Mildred: China Aid Council, 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - 99K - National Society for Medical Research (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Individuals, 1
    - 100 - Grad (Grajdanzev), Andrew J., 1948-1954 (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - 101 - Gorelik, Mordecai, National Theatre Conference, 1943-1952 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - 102 - Fajer, A., 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - 103 - Hiss, Alger, 1946-1952 (Box 8, Folder 164)
    - 104 - Lattimore, Owen: General, 1937-1954 (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - 104A - Lattimore, Owen, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - 104B - Lattimore, Owen: Delhi Conference, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - 105 - Locke, Alain, 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 168)
    - 106 - Smedley, Agnes, 1944-1952 (Box 8, Folder 169)
    - 107 - Slochower, Harry, 1948-1952 (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - 108 - Mayer, Jacques Daniel, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - 109 - Vaz, Zeferino, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - 110 - Wittfogel, Karl, 1937-1954 (Box 8, Folder 173)
    - 111 - Hicks, Granville, 1939-1954 (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - 112 - Padover, Saul K., 1945-1952 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - 113 - Smith, Wilfred Cantwell, 1947-1952 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - 114 - Mirkovic, Mijo, 1934-1952 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - 115 - Condon, Dr. Edward U., 1926-1952 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - 116 - Shapley, Harlow, 1943-1952 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - 117 - Taubenschlag, Rafael, 1940-1952 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - 118 - Wataghin, Gleb, 1941-1952 (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - 119 - Doherty, Mary Louis, 1939-1952 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - 120 - Nogueira, Oracy, 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 183)
    - 121 - Brisks, Rudolf, 1947-1952 (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - 122 - Massera, Jose, 1944-1952 (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - 123 - Norman, Egerton H., 1936-1952 (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - 124 - Barnett, Robert W., 1939-1952 (Box 9, Folder 187)
    - 125 - Haldane, Dr. J. B. S., 1935-1954 (Box 9, Folder 188)
    - 126 - Prochazka, Oldrich, 1947-1952 (Box 9, Folder 189)
    - 127 - Rougier, Louis, 1940-1952 (Box 9, Folder 190)